Eastern Market Oral History Project OHP015
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Eastern Market Oral History Project
1992-1993
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Friends of Eastern Market
OHP015
0.75 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Scope and Contents Materials in this series include transcripts of the interviews. There is no transcript for 15-11. Series 2: Interviews Scope and Contents Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are no duplicate copies of any audio recordings.
Biographical / Historical
Eastern Market is a public market in the Capitol Hill neighborhood of Washington, D.C., which was designed by Adolf Cluss and constructed in 1871.
Custodial History
The Friends of Eastern Market conducted these interviews between 1992 and 1993 as a part of a grant from the D.C. Humanities Council. Duplicates of the original tapes and indexes were transferred to the Library in 1993. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Scope and Contents
From 1992 to 1993, a total of 12 oral history interviews were conducted through the Eastern Market Oral History Project, of which the Library holds resources for nine interviews. The goal of the project was to capture the undocumented history of the Eastern Market, the last vestige of the Washington market system, which for more than 100 years played a vital role in the life of the city. The stories told by the interviewees show the important roles that public markets played in feeding the city throughout the 19th and early 20th centuries, and providing work and a social gathering place while connecting the city and its people to the surrounding countryside. Topics include family history, business, relations between vendors, and neighborhood and industry changes over time. The project was done under a planning grant from the D.C. Community Humanities Council, and Valerie Pawlewicz served as project manager.
Oral History; Neighborhoods; Capitol Hill (Washington, D.C.); Markets; Businesspeople
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts of the interviews. There is no transcript for 15-11.
  - Jessie Buscher, 1992 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ray Bowers, 1992 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ernest Higgins, 1992 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chris Calomiris, 1992 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thomas J. Cooper, 1992 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harry Hodges, 1992 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Esther Hodges, 1993 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Charles Glasgow, 1993 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charles Sherzer, 1993 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are no duplicate copies of any audio recordings.
  - Jessie Buscher, 1992 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 15-01)
  - Ray Bowers, 1992 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 15-02)
  - Ernest Higgins, 1992 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 15-03)
  - Chris Calomiris, 1992 August 24 (Box 2, Folder 15-04)
  - Thomas J. Cooper, 1992 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 15-05)
  - Harry Hodges, 1992 December 16 (Box 2, Folder 15-07)
  - Esther Hodges, 1993 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 15-08)
  - Charles Glasgow, 1993 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 15-09)
  - David Fowler (Box 2, Folder 15-11)
  - Charles Sherzer, 1993 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 15-12)